In what industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Real estate.
Well, I'm the CEO of
insurance and risk management and academic.
I manage 45,000 apartment units.
What has been the biggest deal that
you've ever closed in real estate so far?
Eleven and a half million.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
The most amount of money that
I've ever made in a single year?
Um...
Is it like seven or eight figures?
Yeah, in the right, yeah.
Top of the morning.
It's a beautiful day here in the Sunshine State.
Orlando, Florida.
Winter Park.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I have a social media agency.
It kind of happened by accident,
but I've always been a hustler.
And, you know, I've just
always been really good with people.
Something that kind of got me here
was just really being able to take my
expertise of people and being able to hang out with
people that are 10 years or 20 years older than me.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
The most amount of money that I just made in
a single year was last year we did three million.
That was the biggest year.
And previous to that, you know, we
had been continuously growing every single year.
We haven't had a year we haven't
grown, but that was our biggest year.
And this year I want to do five.
So what would you say is the biggest
difference between a six and a seven figure business?
That's where the leadership comes in, because you
can run a six figure business all by yourself.
You can be the chief executive of
everything and have a six figure business.
But once you hit that seven figure mark, you can,
at least for me as an agency, really training people,
building a team and just having the patience, you
know, with people that, you know, are almost there.
They're just stuck a little bit.
Being able to also build that trust with your team to know that
they're putting all their efforts in to build quality fulfillment for your clients.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, question for you. Are you a business owner?
I'm a CEO.
A CEO.
So we started a channel in Austin,
Texas, that we have 1.4 million followers.
Can we go around asking business owners
a few questions on their advice to entrepreneurs?
Can we ask you a few questions?
Sure.
Awesome.
My first question for you, sir.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Technology.
Yeah. What are you doing exactly right now?
Well, I'm the CEO of Frontline Performance Group, and
we provide a software platform to the hospitality industry primarily.
Also some travel.
So what is your best advice to
anybody starting a software company in today's world?
Know the marketplace that you plan to sell it to.
Better than you know the technology.
Because anyone can build technology, but if you don't know how to
sell it, you're not going to be able to make any money.
What has been your secret to sales throughout your career?
Knowing who you're selling to is critically important.
So do a lot of
research before you approach a customer.
And you got to believe in what you're selling.
If there's something in your product that you are
not sure of, you won't be able to sell it.
It'll show up in the pitch.
And lastly, you have to be direct.
You have to figure out how
to be diplomatic and also very direct.
Because the people that you're talking to
hear a lot of stuff all the time.
And if they don't believe what you're saying.
And if you're not cutting to the chase.
You're not cutting to the point.
You're wasting their time.
And I'll give you one tip.
This is a very important tip that I
learned from the best salesperson I've ever met.
When you're in a meeting with a prospective client.
And then you know it always
goes, okay, we'll follow up with you.
Pull out your phone and say,
let's set that appointment right now.
Even if you're on the phone, let's book it now.
Even if it changes, you have them locked in.
You don't have to chase them.
In 60 seconds, what is the blueprint
to becoming a millionaire in today's world?
You have to own either equity
in a business or start a business.
So when you're young, go work for some
young companies that are willing to give you some
equity and then give them everything you've got.
I did it twice.
This is my second time where I didn't start
the company, but I'm a partner in the company
purely on sweat equity because of the
skillset I've developed and the value I bring.
But if you don't have equity, you don't have wealth.
What do you think is the best industry that
people should be looking to get into in today's
world?
Applied AI.
Find something very simple.
Think of it as a utility that can
be fully automated by AI and then license it.
Excuse me, sir.
Yeah.
Question for you.
If you were to go back to when you
were in either high school or college and you're having
a conversation with your 20 year old self,
what's the best piece of advice that you would
tell your younger self?
Don't become a nightclub promoter.
Yeah.
Is that what you're doing right now?
That's what I did for 10 years.
Yeah.
What industry are you working in right now?
Now I'm in the humanitarian space.
Yeah.
So I run a nonprofit.
You're an entrepreneur.
What's your best advice to anybody
who's starting a business in today's world?
We worked incredibly hard.
My friend also is an entrepreneur.
We worked a hundred hours a week and a
lot of the people don't seem to be willing to
work that hard these days.
They want to play video games.
They want to go to the movies.
There's less drive and determination that
I see in many of today's entrepreneurs.
Look, we're just trying to go out for a spin.
We're trying to go out for some
lunch and it doesn't matter where we go.
It doesn't matter if you're going to the bathroom.
It doesn't matter if you're going to lunch.
It doesn't matter if you're parking the car.
If you have the look and we see you
have a good energy, there's a good chance we're coming
up to you for an interview.
Yeah.
Bill Holm.
How are you?
Jim.
James.
So Jack.
Hey, Jack.
How are you?
Hey, I'm Josh.
Hey, how are you?
I'm good.
In what industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Insurance and risk management and academics.
A little bit unusual because I do have a
whole career in academics and then a whole career
in business.
So you're a business owner?
Oh yeah.
You're a business owner?
Yeah.
We developed over the years what's
called the National Alliance for Insurance Education
and Research.
It's like a CPA type program for
people in the business being agents, companies, adjusters.
And now we have five different programs.
What's your best advice to anybody
who's starting a business in today's world?
Show growth.
You have to grow even if you're a little bit.
Nobody wants to invest in a shrinking business, right?
So you have to have a
business that sort of inspires somebody.
And keeping good people.
That's a big thing because when you hire
new people and they meet other people in your
organization, they say, well, I've been here 14 years.
I've been here 10 years.
I've been here nine years.
That has a big impact on people.
Excellence is a lot of small things done well.
And there's an old adage, you know, we
don't trip over mountains, we trip over molehills.
So it's the little things that make the big difference.
How important has it been for you
surrounding yourself with the right people throughout
your career?
Oh, it's crucial.
People are your greatest asset and your greatest liability.
Good people will build all
around you, will make you better.
And a few bad people will destroy your business.
What has been your secret to sales throughout your career?
So you have to be what
I would call the uncommon man.
Now you don't want to be weird.
Weird is not good.
There's a fine line between uncommon and weird.
People have to respect you first.
Now, why should I buy anything from you?
That's it.
If you were to go back to when you
were in either high school or college and you're having
a conversation with your 20 year old self,
what is the best piece of advice that you
would tell your younger self?
Follow your passion.
Your passion is always right.
That will guide you more
than school will, anybody's opinions will.
If you can follow your gut,
you don't have to follow anything else.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
So I actually pursued my career in marketing.
I was in the marketing industry.
I pursued a career in sport and exercise science.
And now I'm a life alignment coach.
So I kind of deal with everything
from physical fitness to nutrition to life purpose.
What's your best advice to any
entrepreneur starting a business in today's world?
You need to know more.
You need to know that you know
more about your business than anybody else does.
Because people will try to tell you what
they think you should do for your business, but
you need to do what you know is best.
Stack your knowledge.
You can always learn more and
you can always learn from other people.
And I think that people don't understand that.
You come to a point where help is okay.
It's okay to ask for help.
It took me a really long time to really
understand that concept to where you learn from experience.
And if you can't go out and get
more experiences, then you're always going to plateau.
What's going on guys?
We are out here in Winter Park, Orlando.
I'm here with Trey.
He's a 17 year old beast already
getting into the entrepreneurship game early on.
And right now we're actually
about to go interview his grandfather.
Tell us a little bit about your grandfather,
what we're going to talk to him about.
So my grandfather's big in the commercial
space for real estate in Winter Park.
He owns a lot of a place called Park Ave.
Which is a big, big place.
It's a huge shopping district down here.
There's a lot of commercial buildings that
you'll see down later on Park Ave.
I'm sure they'll show you all
when they go around Winter Park.
But he does just, he's big in real
estate and he loves, you know, young kids starting
businesses and that's where I am right now.
In what industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I didn't know what I wanted to do in college.
I got my service obligation over with and
then I went to the real estate business.
It wasn't my dream, but it was a vehicle that
I had and I liked the ability to deal with
different people, different product.
And I just grew it from there.
Over a few mistakes, obviously, and
just kept growing and meeting and growing.
And here I am today, 50 years later, same business.
Yeah.
So you're a business owner?
Yes.
I own this building and I own the business.
I manage 45,000 apartment units.
What's the number one thing that you
would tell someone who's pursuing starting out in
real estate in today's world?
You never spend what you don't
have to get what you don't need.
So you don't risk a lot of money.
Take it a step at a
time and you watch other people.
Copy a successful person.
What have they done to get where they are?
And one of the rules is don't overthink.
Don't over leverage.
Don't get yourself backed up and then
you can't make decisions if you have financial
stress.
You don't have to have a lot of money.
Don't over leverage.
Step at a time.
Build a business.
In 60 seconds, what is the blueprint
to becoming a millionaire in today's world?
Study successful people that are in the same
market you're in or the same avenue you're
in and learn what they do and try to
emulate them and start in the bottom and work yourself
up step by step by step.
It's a two point game.
No three pointers.
Two point game.
Once in a while you have a three pointer.
There's no fast way to this.
There is a few people but
that's not the market there is today.
What's going on guys?
Yeah, we just wrapped up filming with a
real estate mogul out here in Orlando, Florida.
And actually when we were interviewing him
at his office, there was a commercial real
estate specialist.
I think she may be a broker or an agent
and we saw her in the office and she asked what
we were kind of doing and what we were filming.
She let us know about what she was doing.
So she said, Hey, I want
you guys to come to this location.
We'll shoot an interview.
She wants to give us some games.
So let's go.
What industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
Real estate.
What are you doing exactly?
So I was recently specializing in commercial
real estate and investments, but now I have
moved on to doing high end
residential for entire subdivisions and golf communities.
What has been the biggest deal that
you've ever closed in real estate so far?
11 and a half million.
This was through a client
that I was working with consistently.
He owned an asset portfolio which had hotels in it.
So it was a country and in suites in Ocala.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
After gross, I'm not sure.
But I can tell you that there have been.
I've made $75,000 a month.
In your opinion, how can someone really
break into the commercial real estate industry in
today's world?
So I own a commercial real estate leads team
that I've had about 40 agents over the last
two years or so.
And I tell them because a lot of them
are naturally new in the industry is that you
can let people know that you're new, but don't
be scared to either get back to that client
when they ask questions that you don't know.
And also use your resources, hire a mentor, get
a coach for yourself to be able to make
the movement through the process that you're going through.
What has been your secret to sales?
Throughout your career, providing high quality service
to the clients because in the real
estate industry, you don't have
work if you don't have clients.
And if you have clients,
you need to service them effectively.
So that way they're happy with the work,
which is going to ultimately build a referral basis
because you don't want to have to rely
on having to stomp the pavement and having to
be in front of people consistently because it's
going to take away from the time that
you need to be able to meet
people that you are building relationships with.
How many businesses in total have you ever owned before?
Nine.
What do you think are the best three
industries that people should be looking to get into
in 2023?
I think AI is going to blow up.
It's going to take a lot of market share
from people's actual jobs and it's going to be
able to support a lot of people's jobs.
So I think AI is number one.
Number two, I think being a creator,
content creator, it's building a personal brand so
you can monetize in so many different ways.
And number three is always going to be real estate.
It's always been here.
It's going to stay here and it's going to
continue to be one of the best and most lucrative
things that you can do.
What's your number one piece of advice
to any content creator in today's world?
Lose your ego.
A lot of content creators start making money.
They start being validated by the amount
of people that are following them and they
become egotistical.
And one, the audience can feel that
and they start kind of separating themselves.
And two, like the problem is with that,
you really don't think about your business because
you're only thinking about yourself and your ego.
And so you lose a lot of opportunities
and you start getting lazy sometimes or you start
thinking that you're above it or better than.
And so I see a lot
of people's demise happening from ego.
What's your best advice to any creator kind
of like seeking that they're trying to like
monetize as a creator?
The last one is brand deals.
You think it's the first one.
It's the last one.
The first one is probably affiliate marketing
because you can create great deals and from
there get brand deals, right?
The second one is creating your own
stuff, creating your own course, creating your own
offer, creating your own service, creating your
own merch, but build something for yourself.
You've done one of the hardest
things there is in capturing attention.
Now that you have attention, you've got
to sell something that people want because they're
following you for a reason, right?
Whether it's because you're cool or whatever,
then create merch, whether it's because you're
solving problems, then create consulting
or a service or a course.
Like create something for yourself instead
of just always focusing on like, hopefully
I get a deal because you're going to be
misrepresented and you're not going to be paid what you're
worth if you're going for brand deals.
How can someone really like leverage AI for their business?
So right now there's so many different things
happening with AI and it's just the beginning,
right?
Like ChatGPT was one thing.
Now GPT-4 is another thing.
Now you're seeing like automated
like agents coming in through that.
And so if you're in business, you can
use AI to facilitate and systemize and make your
job easier.
Think of it as like an assistant, right?
It can help you speed up.
And make your stuff more efficient.
And if you're in trying to create money from
that, you can use AI to sell services by maximizing
that with AI so you can simplify the time,
the system and the effort and focus on getting
more clients.
Guys, that wraps up today's video.
Make sure to leave a like and subscribe
for tons of amazing content coming soon and click
here to watch us going around Houston
asking Houston millionaires how they became wealthy.